# Juan Esteban Llanos Vera

**English-Japanese Translator** 

#### Professional curriculum

I stand out for my empathic character; which allows me a great capacity to adapt, acquire responsibilities and the ability to work as a team. In addition, I have the ability to carry out my work in a cordial atmosphere of respect and harmony; facilitating decision-making and good relations with all levels of the organization. I have extensive experience in trust positions, problem solving and ability to work under pressure. High moral values, enterprising, proactive. Responsible and committed to the work entrusted.

### **Contact details**

Date of Birth: January 16<sup>th</sup>, 1979

Nationality: Chilean

Contact: +569 87718040

Email address: esteban.llanosv@gmail.com

Main address: San Mauricio 3176, Puente Alto, Santiago, Chile.

#### Academic background

1985 – 1996 Liceo Andrés Bello.

Puente alto, Santiago, Chile

**Primary and Secondary Education** 

1997 – 2001 Universidad de Santiago de Chile (USACH)

Santiago, Chile

Bachelor in Linguistics applied to Translation

2001:

- Professional Title of English-Spanish Translator
- Major in English Spanish Japanese Translation

2000:

Three semesters of studies in the Portuguese language.

#### Career experience

## SDL Chile S.A. 2017 – May 2022

**Senior Translation Manager** 

- Supervision of the operation of the local office as well as the translation projects of the clients; emphasizing quality and stipulated delivery times.
- Assistance to the people in different positions to solve their problems and meet the demands of customers.
- Recruitment of new internal and external talent to increase both internal and external capacity to deliver a better service to customers and their needs.
- Communication and implementation of new initiatives and/or technologies within the office to adapt to changes within the organization based on long-term strategies.
- Coordination of all contractual and human resources aspects of local employees, such as vacations, salary increases, work-related problems, etc.
- Development and implementation of quality measures to address customer complaints and improve results and regain trust.
- Provide different pieces of training to the different translation team to transfer knowledge and help them excel in their job positions.

### SDL Chile S.A. 2013 – 2017

**Translation Line Manager** 

- Job position related to the management of a translation team in charge of different clients. The main tasks of this position consisted of assigning translation projects according to the area of specialization and the deadlines agreed with clients in order to deliver top quality.
- I was also in charge of all the administrative side of the projects, such as payments to vendors, the creation of instruction guides, and solving any issue that may arise during the life cycle of a project.
- In addition to administrative tasks, part of my day was focused on production. That is to say, translating and editing different texts for the numerous clients that we managed as a team. Among these clients are: Google, Dell-EMC, Marsh, HSBC, Intel, Motorola, Starbucks, Sony, Disney, Ovations, Molina Healthcare, WellCare, etc. 5 years of experiencing translating for these clients.
- Provide pieces of training to the team to transfer knowledge and help them grow in their careers within the company.

# **Lionbridge Chile Traducciones 2003 – 2013**

**Project Manager** 

- Assignment, coordination and supervision of translation projects for different clients;
   emphasizing quality and stipulated delivery times.
- Coordination of external vendors.

 Personalized attention to a portfolio of direct clients, those who require more direct attention due to their demands.

# Lionbridge Chile Traducciones 2002- 2003

**Spanish-English Freelance Translator.** 

- Technical translations for several clients (such as Lowe's, LRN, Ovations, Samsung, EMC, etc.) in the translations of different projects and topics.
- Deployment of various translation tools to achieve an excellent final product.
- Integration of other skills related to translation tasks to improve the final product.

#### **Proficiencies and Strengths**

Languages

SPEAKING WRITING

Spanish Native Native

English Advance Advance

Portuguese Basic Intermediate

Japanese Basic Basic

#### **Additional skills**

- Microsoft Office Medium to advanced knowledge.
- Efficient, accurate and detail-oriented
- Translation management software skills (Trados Studio Translation Workspace Trados SDLX Wordfast Passolo TMX Xbench Transistor)
- Ability to find solutions to problems creatively, proactively, and to work under pressure
- Ability to work in teams and to work independently, with little or no supervision
- Strong written and oral communication skills

#### <u>Interests</u>

Technology, music, videogames, movies/TV shows, social meetings, science, and languages.